<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abraham P. Vinod</title>
    <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Abraham P. Vinod</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 18:46:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://abyvinod.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A gentle tutorial to the difference of convex optimization</title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/dcvx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 18:46:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/dcvx/</guid>
      <description>This Jupyter notebook-based blog post can be setup in your local machine as follows:
 Jupyter notebook (Use right click and &amp;lsquo;Save Link as&amp;rsquo;) Conda environment file  It uses the problem of placing a fixed number of round smaller circles in a large circle as a nonlinear (non-convex) optimization problem. It was through setting up and solving the resulting difference of convex optimization problem using CVXPY.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SReachTools: A MATLAB Toolbox for stochastic reachability computation</title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/sreachtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/sreachtools/</guid>
      <description>SReachTools is an open-source (GPLv3) stochastic reachability toolbox, written in MATLAB. See this project post to know more about this mathematical framework for generating probabilistic guarantees of safety and performance.
For safety-critical applications, it is important that we construct either exact or underapproximations of the set of safe initial states. We do not want to be over-confident in our safety declarations, i.e., declare an initial state safe when it is not really safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety under uncertainty and constraints</title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/project/stochreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/project/stochreach/</guid>
      <description>Automation, typically, refers to the use of an onboard computer to drives a system to optimize some objective. It makes our day-to-day life simpler and efficient, for example, in transportation (autopilot systems and self-driving cars), space applications, biomedical applications, power grid, and the list goes on and on. However, as we hand over more and more control to the automation, we naturally seek guarantees of safety and performance. After all, we do not want to spend billions of dollar in R&amp;amp;D and develop an automation that may cause harm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic motion planning via probabilistic occupancy function</title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/stochmotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/stochmotion/</guid>
      <description>The video below shows the example discussed in our CDC 2018 paper. The successive convexification-based planner computes these trajectories within $0.25$ seconds (sampling time). The obstacle motion prediction is done on-the-fly using my work on probabilistic occupancy function.
 The colored circles are obstacles that we must avoid. The obstacles have known stochastic dynamics. The figure on the right shows the $\alpha$-probability occupied sets. The black dot is the current robot location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic target capture via forward stochastic reachability</title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/stochtarget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/stochtarget/</guid>
      <description>Given a stochastic model for a (non-adversarial) threat quadrotor, we utilize forward stochastic reachability to construct trajectories with maximum probability of capture for a pursuer quadrotor.
Experiment 1: Robustness to threat quadrotor {{% alert warning %}} You may want to mute the YouTube video to avoid the sound of the quadrotors {{% /alert %}}
{{&amp;lt; youtube eFGg7U7gEQw &amp;gt;}}
Experiment 2: Open-loop control vs receding horizon control {{% alert warning %}} You may want to mute the YouTube video to avoid the sound of the quadrotors {{% /alert %}}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacecraft rendezvous problem</title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/spacecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/post/spacecraft/</guid>
      <description>High-level description We wish to drive a spacecraft (Deputy) towards another spacecraft (Chief) for docking. This problem is known as the spacecraft rendezvous and docking problem. It is a common requirement for maintenance and resupply missions in space applications. Due to sensing constraints, we wish that the Deputy stays within a line-of-sight cone with respect to Chief. Further, we wish to achieve the docking in a pre-specified time interval while obeying the physical laws that govern the system and constraints on actuation (limited thrust).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic occupancy via forward stochastic reachability</title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/project/proboccup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/project/proboccup/</guid>
      <description>{{% toc %}}
High-level description For reliable autonomy under uncertainty, we must have efficient ways to estimate event likelihood given a stochastic system model.
Existing methods  Use sampling-based methods like Monte-Carlo simulation. Hoever, this approach only have asymptotic convergence guarantees. Compute the probability density via convolutions when the dynamics is linear. However, this iterative method requires gridding for numerical evalution of the convolution integral. Further, its accuracy degrades over long time horizons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://abyvinod.github.io/author/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abyvinod.github.io/author/admin/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher with experience in control, optimization, and reinforcement learning. My research goal is to develop safe autonomy under uncertainty and constraints using minimal computational effort. Safe autonomy can have wide impact ranging from bio-medical devices and transportation to space applications.
Currently, I am a Postdoctoral Research Fellow at the Institute for Computational Engineering and Sciences, the University of Texas at Austin with Dr. Ufuk Topcu. I received my PhD in Engineering (Systems and Control) at the University of New Mexico, with Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>